Name : SATHISH RAJENDRAN

DOB : 24-04-1991 Nationality : Indian

E- Mail : sathishmeltronics@gmail.com

Mobile (UAE) : 00971507030514

00971547969145



ELECTRONIC TECHNICIAN (ET)

Career Overview:

7+ Years Electronic Testing (ET) is responsible for the maintenance, inspecting, testing and repair of electrical and electronic equipment and automated systems on-board - advises the Technical Section Leader on installation, maintenance, repair, testing, and verification of these equipment and systems. Responsibilities also include ensuring that the explosion proof integrity of installations and equipment within hazardous zones is maintained.

Department/Functional Area - Installation / Maintenance / Operations / Repair/Telecom

Industries - Defense / Military / Government

Experience:

Lab Technician (ELECTRONICS)

HCL Technologies
Project Title- ELTS- Emirates Land Tactical System (UAE MILITARY)

Feb 2017 – PRESENT UAE- ABU DHABI



Responsibilities:

- Hardware Wiring Assembly and Electronic Modules Installation in Military Vehicles.
- Radio programming, Testing and troubleshooting Tactical Radios(RF)
- Diagnose and resolve faults on all radios equipment, including vehicle mounted radio Equipment and associated components.
- Electronic/Electric maintenance according to programmed maintenance system (IFS).
- Supporting for Military Vehicles integration and testing.
- Ensuring all electronic test equipment is available and calibrated.
- Travel to customer locations to perform testing when needed.
- Checking and calibrating the fire and gas detecting equipment, and other warning and alarm systems on board.
- Reporting progress and documenting all work activities as per defined process.
- Ensuring that the Emergency Shutdown System is in working order at all times.
- Maintain and update a file of drawings and manuals for the automatic electrical systems and the electronic equipment.
- Ordering of spares and keeping inventory of electronic and electrical components.
- Configuration and testing of radio equipment in the workshop.

Technical Support Executive

Accord Software & Systems Pvt. Ltd Bangalore
Project Title – GNSS Simulator (GPS) Navigation System (INDIAN MILITARY)

May 2014 to Jan 2017 India - Bangalore



Responsibilities:

- System Level Integration Testing & Debugging.
- Supporting for Hardware Electronics Design Team.
- Develop test plan and procedures wiring diagram for electronic systems.
- Review test procedures and instructions before starting the system testing process.
- System installation Onsite work in Customer Place.
- Co-operate in enhancing safety standards.
- Testing with faultfinding, measuring, and testing of electronic and programmable equipment.
- Working with electronic / electrical systems and equipment.
- Answering technical questions with respect to the electrical systems and equipment.
- Responsible for the safe and efficient execution of duties in accordance with the management system
- Conversant with rules and regulations for electronic / electrical equipment conversant with computerized maintenance systems.
- Build-up and maintain personal competencies relevant to client's products, including familiarity
 With current and future hardware configurations, likely problems and their solutions.

Testing Technician

ISRO SATELLITE for Aidin Technologies Pvt.Ltd Bangalore Project Title: Sky Scanning Mechanism (Astrosat) (ISRO)

Oct 2012 to April 2014 India - Bangalore



Responsibilities:

- Supporting for Spacecraft Scientist Engineer (Testing Activities).
- EMI, EMC and temperature testing.
- Coordinated with teach team to develop integration plans and technical profiles.
- Review and interpret schematics, blueprints, and technical manuals in the performance of repair, troubleshooting, and technical analysis duties for reparable units and tests stations.

Testing Engineer

Meltronics Systemtech Pvt. Ltd Bangalore
Project Title: Automated Test Equipment (ATE) (INDIAN AIR FORCE AIRCRAFTS)

June 2011 to Oct 2012 India - Bangalore



Responsibilities:

- Board bring up and helping assembly team for populating components.
- Automated Testing Equipment (ATE) LRU Testing.
- Installation and service of ATE at customer site (Indian Air Force and Navy).
- Ordering of spares and keeping inventory of electronic and electrical components
- Modify electrical schematics, isometrics, and electrical wiring diagrams as necessary
- Maintain a file of drawings and manuals for the automatic electrical systems and the electronic equipment
- Inspecting and testing all electronic equipment installed on-board

Educational History

- Diploma in Electrical & Electronics Engineering (HND) Passed out in the year 2011 with 82% First class with Distinction.
- Passed higher secondary with first class 64% in 2009.
- Passed SSLC with first class 69% from state board in 2007.

Skills

- ORCAD Schematics, MS Word, Excel, Power Point
- RS 232, RS 422, RS 485
- Technically Lead the team
- Bare PCB analysis
- Analytical skill
- Problem solving skills

Instruments Used:

- Spectrum Analyzer
- CRO
- Multimeter

- SYSTEM: Window XP, win 7, Win 10
- Knowledge in RF Testing
- Power Supply
- Signal Generator

HIGHLIGHTS

- Willing to Travel and Work Anywhere in World
- Clients worked Place Indian Air Force, Indian navy, Indian Military, UAE Zayed Military city, ISRO Bangalore

Personal Details:

Name : Sathish Father Name : Rajendran

Present Address : Salam Street, Lulu Center Abu Dhabi.

Permanent Address : India
Marital Status : Single
Passport : N9089019

Skype id : Sathish Rajendran

Languages Known : English, Kannda, and Tamil